<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>We Don't Just Build Websites — We Build Lead-Generation Machines for Your Business on WEBVAM Studio</title><link>https://webvam.cz/en/</link><description>Recent content in We Don't Just Build Websites — We Build Lead-Generation Machines for Your Business on WEBVAM Studio</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-US</language><atom:link href="https://webvam.cz/en/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Static Website (Hugo)</title><link>https://webvam.cz/en/services/static-websites/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://webvam.cz/en/services/static-websites/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="a-fast-professional-website-for-your-business-in-czechia">A fast, professional website for your business in Czechia&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Running a business in Czech Republic as an expat or international company? You need a website that loads fast, looks professional, and helps Czech customers find you. A static website delivers all of this — without the overhead of complex CMS systems.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="what-you-get">What you get&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Google PageSpeed 95–100/100&lt;/strong> — speed is a ranking factor in Google, and your visitors will notice&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Zero security vulnerabilities&lt;/strong> — no database, no CMS, no attack surface for hackers&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Bilingual by design&lt;/strong> — Czech and English versions built in, so you reach both local and international clients&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>SEO-ready from day one&lt;/strong> — proper meta tags, structured data, and fast loading for top Google rankings&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Fully responsive&lt;/strong> — looks perfect on mobile, tablet, and desktop&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>No CMS maintenance costs&lt;/strong> — no plugin updates, no security patches, no downtime&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="who-its-for">Who it&amp;rsquo;s for&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Expat entrepreneurs&lt;/strong> — consultants, coaches, freelancers who need a professional online presence&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>International companies&lt;/strong> — opening a Czech branch and need a local website&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Startups&lt;/strong> — landing pages for product launches and investor presentations&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Professional services&lt;/strong> — law firms, accounting, real estate, medical practices&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Digital nomads&lt;/strong> — portfolio and service pages for your Czech-based business&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="how-we-work">How we work&lt;/h3>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Consultation in English&lt;/strong> — tell us about your business, goals, and target audience&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Content strategy&lt;/strong> — we plan the site structure, pages, and keywords for the Czech market&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Design and development&lt;/strong> — we build a modern, responsive website on the Hugo platform&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>SEO setup&lt;/strong> — we optimize for Google Czech Republic and set up Google Business Profile&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Launch and handover&lt;/strong> — we deploy to reliable hosting with SSL and walk you through everything&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="why-hugo-instead-of-wordpress">Why Hugo instead of WordPress?&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Hugo is a static site generator used by companies worldwide. Unlike WordPress, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t need a database, PHP server, or constant updates. The result is a website that&amp;rsquo;s faster, more secure, and cheaper to maintain. If you don&amp;rsquo;t need daily content changes or an online store, a static site is the smarter choice.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>CMS Website (WordPress)</title><link>https://webvam.cz/en/services/cms-websites/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://webvam.cz/en/services/cms-websites/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="manage-your-website-content--no-developer-needed">Manage your website content — no developer needed&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Need to update products, publish blog posts, or change prices regularly? WordPress gives you full control over your website content through an intuitive admin panel. We set it up so you can manage everything yourself — in English.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="whats-included">What&amp;rsquo;s included&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>English admin panel&lt;/strong> — manage your content in a language you&amp;rsquo;re comfortable with&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>E-commerce (WooCommerce)&lt;/strong> — sell online with Czech payment gateways (card, bank transfer)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Blog and news&lt;/strong> — publish articles to build authority and attract customers from Google&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Bilingual content&lt;/strong> — Czech and English versions via WPML or Polylang to reach local and international clients&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>SEO tools&lt;/strong> — Yoast SEO or Rank Math for visibility in Czech Google results&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Contact forms&lt;/strong> — inquiries delivered straight to your inbox&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="who-benefits-from-wordpress">Who benefits from WordPress&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Online stores&lt;/strong> — from small catalogs to hundreds of products, with Czech payment integration&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Companies with frequent updates&lt;/strong> — prices, events, team changes, portfolios&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Service businesses&lt;/strong> — online booking, client portfolios, testimonials&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Restaurants and hospitality&lt;/strong> — menus, opening hours, reservations&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Organizations and communities&lt;/strong> — events, newsletters, member sections&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="what-you-get-at-launch">What you get at launch&lt;/h3>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>WordPress installation&lt;/strong> on reliable hosting with daily backups&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Custom design&lt;/strong> — tailored to your brand and target audience&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Essential plugins&lt;/strong> — security, SEO, forms, anti-spam, performance&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Training session&lt;/strong> — we show you how to add content, products, and images&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>30 days of support&lt;/strong> — we help with any questions after launch&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="security-and-maintenance">Security and maintenance&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>WordPress is secure when properly configured. We install a firewall, set up automatic backups, and keep everything updated. If you&amp;rsquo;d rather not deal with the technical side, our monthly maintenance service handles it all.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>SEO Optimization</title><link>https://webvam.cz/en/services/seo-optimization/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://webvam.cz/en/services/seo-optimization/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="get-found-by-czech-customers--even-in-english">Get found by Czech customers — even in English&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>You have a great business in Czech Republic, but local customers can&amp;rsquo;t find you on Google? SEO optimization bridges the gap between your English-language business and the Czech market. We help you rank in Google.cz and attract customers who are searching for exactly what you offer.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="what-seo-optimization-includes">What SEO optimization includes&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Technical audit&lt;/strong> — we find and fix issues that prevent Google from ranking your site&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Keyword research&lt;/strong> — we identify what your Czech and international customers actually search for&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>On-page optimization&lt;/strong> — titles, meta descriptions, headings, structured data&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Speed optimization&lt;/strong> — Core Web Vitals, image compression, caching&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Local SEO&lt;/strong> — Google Business Profile, Google Maps visibility for your area&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Content strategy&lt;/strong> — what content to create to attract and convert visitors&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="why-seo-matters-for-expat-businesses">Why SEO matters for expat businesses&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Over 90% of Czech consumers search for services on Google&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Even English-speaking clients in Czechia use Google.cz — your site needs to rank there&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Local SEO brings customers from your neighborhood — &amp;ldquo;english dentist Prague&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;expat accountant Brno&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Organic traffic is the most cost-effective customer acquisition channel&lt;/li>
&lt;li>SEO works 24/7 — unlike ads that stop the moment you pause the budget&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="bilingual-seo--our-expertise">Bilingual SEO — our expertise&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Your customers include both Czech speakers and English speakers. We optimize your site for both audiences: Czech keywords for the local market and English keywords for the expat community. Proper hreflang setup, separate indexing, and a keyword strategy for each language.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Support &amp; Maintenance</title><link>https://webvam.cz/en/services/support-maintenance/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://webvam.cz/en/services/support-maintenance/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="focus-on-your-business--we-take-care-of-the-website">Focus on your business — we take care of the website&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Running a business in a foreign country is complex enough. You shouldn&amp;rsquo;t have to worry about WordPress updates, security patches, or website downtime. We handle the technical side so you can focus on what you do best.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="what-monthly-maintenance-includes">What monthly maintenance includes&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Updates&lt;/strong> — WordPress core, plugins, and themes always up to date&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Backups&lt;/strong> — regular backups so you never lose your data&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Security&lt;/strong> — firewall, threat monitoring, malware protection&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>24/7 monitoring&lt;/strong> — if your site goes down, we know immediately and fix it&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Content changes&lt;/strong> — need to update text, images, or prices? Just send us an email&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>English-speaking support&lt;/strong> — we respond within 24 hours, in English&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="why-ongoing-maintenance-matters">Why ongoing maintenance matters&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>43% of cyber attacks target small business websites&lt;/li>
&lt;li>An unpatched vulnerability can expose customer data and damage your reputation&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Slow websites lose customers — every extra second of load time reduces conversions by 7%&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Website downtime means lost orders and lost trust&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="maintenance-plans">Maintenance plans&lt;/h3>
&lt;table>
 &lt;thead>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;th>&lt;/th>
 &lt;th>Basic&lt;/th>
 &lt;th>Standard&lt;/th>
 &lt;th>Premium&lt;/th>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;/thead>
 &lt;tbody>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>Updates&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>✓&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>✓&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>✓&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>Backups&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>weekly&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>daily&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>daily&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>Content changes&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>1h/month&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>3h/month&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>5h/month&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>24/7 monitoring&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>✓&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>✓&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>✓&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>Priority support&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>—&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>✓&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>✓&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>SEO reporting&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>—&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>—&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>✓&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;h3 id="why-choose-us">Why choose us&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>We don&amp;rsquo;t manage hundreds of websites on an assembly line. Each client gets personal attention from a dedicated specialist. You know your contact by name, communicate in English, and get a human response — not a ticket number.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Domain &amp; Hosting</title><link>https://webvam.cz/en/services/domain-hosting/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://webvam.cz/en/services/domain-hosting/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="domain-hosting-and-email--all-in-one-place">Domain, hosting, and email — all in one place&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Setting up a .cz domain, configuring hosting, and creating professional email addresses can be confusing — especially when the documentation is in Czech. We handle everything for you: one point of contact, one invoice, zero hassle.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="what-we-set-up-for-you">What we set up for you&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Domain registration&lt;/strong> — .cz, .com, .eu and dozens of other extensions&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Reliable hosting&lt;/strong> — SSD storage, high uptime, automatic backups&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>SSL certificate&lt;/strong> — encrypted HTTPS connection for security and customer trust&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Professional email&lt;/strong> — &lt;a href="mailto:info@yourcompany.cz">info@yourcompany.cz&lt;/a> instead of a Gmail address&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>DNS configuration&lt;/strong> — proper setup without the technical headache&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>English-speaking support&lt;/strong> — help whenever you need it, in your language&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="why-go-through-us">Why go through us&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Single contact&lt;/strong> — website, domain, hosting, and email from one provider&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Done-for-you setup&lt;/strong> — no need to figure out DNS records, MX entries, or SSL certificates&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Transparent pricing&lt;/strong> — no hidden fees or automatic price increases at renewal&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Free migration&lt;/strong> — if your website is hosted elsewhere, we&amp;rsquo;ll move it for free&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="which-domain-to-choose">Which domain to choose&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>For businesses targeting Czech customers, we recommend .cz — it builds trust with local clients and signals relevance for local SEO. For international reach, .com or .eu are solid choices. We&amp;rsquo;ll check availability and help you pick the right one.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Contact</title><link>https://webvam.cz/en/contact/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://webvam.cz/en/contact/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="how-it-works">How it works&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Send us a message in English — tell us about your business and what you need: a new website, e-commerce, SEO, or ongoing support. We&amp;rsquo;ll get back to you within 24 hours with a tailored proposal. First consultation is free.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="working-hours">Working hours&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Monday–Friday: 9:00–18:00 (CET)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We typically reply to emails and messages within 24 hours. Full communication in English — no language barrier.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Thank you!</title><link>https://webvam.cz/en/thanks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://webvam.cz/en/thanks/</guid><description>&lt;p>Your message has been sent successfully. We will get back to you as soon as possible.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you have an urgent question, contact us directly at &lt;a href="mailto:info@webvam.cz">info@webvam.cz&lt;/a> or via &lt;a href="https://t.me/&amp;#43;420773212221">Telegram&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>